What's up guys, welcome back to my channel.
I hope you're having a lovely day today.
And I hope it gets even better from watching this video.
Today we're chatting all about how to actually become a happy person.
Like how to live a life that's authentic to you.
Meaningful and fulfilling and just a life that you're excited to wake up to.
Because who doesn't want that.
I honestly know a little something about this topic.
Because I used to be so incredibly unhappy.
I was at a mental hospital. I was a bad, bad, bad time.
And I dedicated myself to completely turn my life around.
And actually create a life for myself that I love.
And I'm excited about you really can turn your life around.
But even if your situation is not that dramatic.
Even if you're just in a little bit of a funk.
Or you're just trying to find some tips to be even happier.
You're in the right place.
By the way I have so much to say about this topic.
So if at the end of the video.
You want to see more.
You just let me know
And I'll do a part two
But today we're gonna really dive in
And we're gonna do a strategic step-by-step guide to become happy
I've got some exercises. Some journaling problems.
And I think it's also so important to really understand a topic
To make a difference. So we're going to dive into all of that
But if you're new here
Hi, I'm Nicka. I make videos all about self improvement
And I like to make them very strategic organized to-do list form
So you can actually make a big change
So if that works for you
I would love for you to subscribe and stick around
I also have my social media
If you want to see more of my personal life
And we can keep these chats going also
I finally launched the Notion template
You guys have been waiting for it: it's called a life design planner
So link it down below
If you've been waiting for it
Thank you for your patience.
It's basically where you can set and track your habits.
Your goals and your routines.
And you can also plan your months, your weeks.
Your days and there's so much more.
So I'll leave a link to that below.
As well as a video that I did.
Where I went over the whole system, if you're interested already.
Now let's get into how to actually be happy.
We're gonna start with understanding your core values.
Because I feel that's the most important thing
When it comes to your happiness and it's something
I don't hear many people talk about living a happy life
Means that you're living in accordance with your core values
So when you're committed to your core values
You're naturally prioritizing things that make you feel happy
Things that fulfill you and are important to you
So the simple guide or our compass to happiness is to figure out
What our core values are which we'll get to
And then commit to them and prioritize them
We're going to imagine what it's like
When this is not working when it's the opposite
So we're gonna talk about self-sacrificing
Which is such a common thing to do when you're unhappy
I used to do this
So it basically means you're prioritizing everyone else and what everyone else wants
You're basically a people pleaser
You're doing things that you think you should be doing
And things that you know make you seem like a good girl
And you're successful and you're amazing in the eyes of whoever
And if that's not in alignment with your values
And what you actually find meaningful and important
Of course you're going to be unhappy
Because you are spending so much of your time
Doing the things that you actually don't really care about and don't find meaningful
And what ends up happening is that you literally wake up to a life
That doesn't even feel like your own. You're living someone else's life
So let's say you are born very creative
And let's just imagine your core values are creativity and freedom
That is what actually makes you happy. What makes you feel alive
What makes your life feel meaningful and fulfilling?
But you grew up with a mom whose main priority is status.
And how you all as a family appear to your community.
To the neighborhood, to whoever. And she basically raised you to become a doctor.
So let's say you go along with that.
Let's say you don't wanna disappoint your mom.
And you want to please everyone, and you go into medicine.
Obviously you're not gonna be very happy.
Because medicine is not really a career that I would choose for someone.
Who's very creative and wants to be free.
It's the opposite of that, just the school part.
A loan would be bearable to someone.
Who just wants to be creative and free.
Let's talk about two really important things.
That might make starting to live in accordance with your values
and prioritizing your happiness a little bit difficult.
And let's dismantle them.
And then we'll get into how to figure out your values number one.
You might feel shame for the values that you have.
Let's say you're someone who wants to make a lot of money.
That is your main priority and your biggest goal in life.
And so when you mention that to other people.
When you talk about it.
A lot of people have a reaction of that shallow.
What about love?
And what about things that are actually meaningful and important?
blah blah blah.
And so it's completely understandable that you would start to feel shame.
And then it's really hard to make those goals happen.
And to keep going even when things get hard.
If you feel shame for wanting that in the first place
And if you feel like you shouldn't want the things that you want
And by the way, making money is not a value.
Making money is either a wish or a want or a goal.
It is not a value.
What your core value could be here
If this is very important to you is like security
Safety. Maybe it's achievement, maybe it's freedom. It's different for everyone.
And when you understand what that core value is
It's so much easier to achieve the things that you want.
Because first of all it kind of gets rid of the shame because.
You get it if I want to make a lot of money.
And my reason is because I want to feel really secure.
And give myself security which I might have never had in my life.
That makes complete sense. I don't feel shame for that.
I'm like I get it.
And also by committing to this value.
It makes achieving these goals so much easier.
Because when you reach hardships and challenges, it doesn't rock the boat as much.
Your core is so strong.
Because you know exactly why you're doing the things that you're doing
And they are so important to you that's why people talk about your Why
Being so important when you're reaching your goals
It's actually all about your values
Another challenge or hard part about this is that your subconscious mind
And often prioritize safety
Over you doing the things that actually bring you fulfillment
That's why change can be so hard
Because it's scary to go out of your comfort zone
And do something that you've never done before
Your subconscious mind is like alarm bells. This is not safe.
This is not familiar.
I have a whole video about this.
So I'll link that here.
The solution to this is just
to make your values conscious to be aware of them.
And you have values in pretty much every category of your life.
Whether that's friendship, relationships, family, career.
The way you spend your free time.
What you do to be active like you have values everywhere.
You might just not be aware of them already.
Now let's actually get into how to figure out your values.
And by the way, this might take a little bit of time.
Like you don't have to do all of this in one sitting.
But I highly recommend either journaling, doing it in your note.
And then you can just keep adding to it.
As you get to know yourself and your happiness more.
So let's start with exploring your happiness, so you're gonna write down.
What has, in the past, when you look at your life,
Brought you the most happiness.
When do you actually really really enjoy yourself and just love living?
Love being here also when were you the most proud of yourself?
And when did you actually feel fulfillment?
And the things you are doing or experiencing.
Or meaning your life was meaningful.
Another really fun exercise you can do is to pretend that you're the happiest.
You've ever been. If you can't do this on your own.
Just by thinking about it or writing about it.
There are so many dream life.
Visualizations and things like that
You can listen to a guided one
And then you can imagine
What your happiest life would look like
And then just write it down
Who are you spending your time with?
What are those people like?
How do you show up differently in those friendships or relationships?
How is your lifestyle different?
How are your hobbies different?
What do you do career wise? Like what actually
Brings you that passion, excitement, and happiness and makes you feel super fulfilled
And like you're living a life that is meaningful
And you're so excited to wake up every day
Just have a very very clear vision of that
Again, you can do the guided visualizations
There are so many for free on YouTube
You can also make
This visual if you want to do like a vision board based on this
Just again imagine that you're living your happiest life
And you're just the happiest you've ever been.
What does that look like?
Get very very granular and go into every single detail.
Nook and cranny that you can find.
Also when you imagine this dream life.
Ask yourself: What am I actually doing differently?
What am I doing more of?
What am I doing less of?
Again that will give you more information and details.
So when you look at everything that you've written.
And again this might take a little bit of time
And it's going to give you a very kind of clear
Idea about your values or at least it's going to point you to them
So if in this dream life vision or everything all the journaling prompts
Did you realize that you actually feel the happiest and the most alive
When you're really creative maybe you work for yourself
When you can afford to travel and just fly
By the seat of your own pants
Is that the expression? Just go anywhere, do whatever you want.
Maybe one of your core values is freedom
That would make sense, right?
If you're heavily career-oriented and you just want to climb this ladder.
And that gives you genuine excitement and happiness.
Maybe one of your core values is achievement.
If you're someone whose relationships are the most important to you.
And that is where you're the happiest.
That is when you shine.
Maybe your core value is connection or belonging.
One of my core values, for example, is security.
It shows up everywhere in my life.
I need to feel secure.
That is why I'm in a relationship that I'm in.
That is why I have this career as an influencer.
But I have something else on the side.
Even though I don't have to just to feel secure.
And like I'm gonna be okay.
Same thing with my finances.
Like I'm so into my budget and saving.
Because again it makes me feel secure.
And there's so many ways that this shows up.
But that is one of my core values for example
And again your values show up in every area of your life
So don't just look at career
Look at every single aspect of your life
Also by the way your values can change as you grow up
Go through life as you experience different things
So just keep that in mind
The last little tip exercise that I have to really figure out
What your values are is to look at your wishes wants and goals
And ask yourself what would having that mean to me?
Let's say one of my biggest goals
Is to make x amounts of money
What would having that mean to me
In my case it would make me feel secure
It would give me security
And that is my core value, by the way
You might have to ask yourself that question
A few times to actually get to the core value
That's another really great way to figure out your values
Especially now if you set goals for yourself for 2024
And you can figure out if those goals are actually meaningful to you
Okay, now that you've got all of this written out
You've done the exercises. You kind of have an idea what your values are
Again, this might take a little bit of time. That's okay
You're gonna write them down
And then you're going to rank them in terms of priority
So obviously number one value is going to be the one
That's most important to you
And the one that's going to be the most important for you
To commit to and stick to
So let's say my values are creativity and freedom.
When I looked at my career.
The way I like to spend my free time.
My lifestyle I really saw that I need creativity and freedom.
And then I also really need security.
I need to have some money on the side.
I need to have a job that's stable.
I need to have a few sources of income.
Whatever it might be, let's then say that when I look at my relationships.
Friendships, family, I can really see that value or feeling of belonging.
Is really important to me.
So we're adding belonging on that list.
And then playfulness as well.
I really see that again in relationships.
I need things to be a little funny quirky.
When I look at my home,
The way I spend my free time,
I know that being playful
Super important to me as well.
So you have the list of these five values.
You ranked them in terms of priority.
And now you're going to look at your life figure out.
How have you been living in accordance with these values?
How are you doing that already?
How are you not living in alignment with those values?
And then how can you change that?
What improvements can you make?
What can you do differently, and it's really crazy.
Because when I did this exercise.
And when I looked back on my life.
And the things that made me really unhappy
Relationships, career moves, lifestyle choices
Everything, it makes so much sense.
And with every single scenario.
I could see that I was not living in accordance with my value.
I was basically doing the opposite.
And it was making me very unhappy.
So it just gives you understanding of
Why certain things don't work for you.
And also a blueprint of what you can now do, what direction.
You should move in, it's honestly pretty simple.
But it is a practice.
Like you practice living in accordance with your values.
And you might make some missteps and be like, okay, I made that decision.
Made me unhappy. So how can I make a different decision?
Now that's actually going to make me happy.
Where I can live my life in accordance with my values.
And feel excited and feel fulfilled.
And like my life is meaningful.
And what I'm doing is meaningful to me.
My camera died. But what I wanted to say
Is that you can start living in accordance with your values today.
And it's so important to do that.
Because so many people are like.
I'm gonna start living a life that actually makes me happy.
When I actually do X, Y, Z.
So an example here, I'm miserable in my job.
It makes me so unhappy.
It sucks all the life out of me.
But I'm going to stay in the job for the next fifteen years.
So that then after that I have the means.
To actually love the life that I want to live.
And obviously it's not realistic for most people.
To quit their job tomorrow or three weeks from now.
You know that is not what I mean.
But you can actually start living in accordance with your values in other ways.
You can start choosing your happiness in the ways that you can.
And changing your job might not be realistic right now.
But it's a domino effect. So for example.
You might start living in accordance with your values.
And really committing and choosing your happiness
When it comes to your free time, your relationships
And let's say you stumble upon knitting
And you realize you have a real real talent
And it's really in alignment with your values
You can do it from anywhere
You can be creative
And you start making things for your friends
They tell their friends and then you open an Etsy shop
And then you start a whole other business
And then at some point you're able to quit your job
Or change your job or whatever it might be
It's a domino effect
And so just focus on the things that you can control
And the things that you can change
And then it will just snowball
That has honestly been my experience
I feel like when you're living in accordance with your values
And you're genuinely so happy
I've really seen that happen to me personally
And so many doors just naturally opened and I started slowly.
Let that first down. I'm going to fall.
And then just take the next step and the next step.
And make sure that each one is something that you're actively choosing.
And it's in accordance with your values and it's making you.
Happy. That is the main point that's making you happy. It is your life.
It is your responsibility.
It might not be fair that you know you've gotten on the wrong path.
Because someone forced you or bulldozed you into it.
Whether it was your parents or whoever, society, whatever.
Sure you can be upset about it, annoyed about it, feel resentful, whatever.
But at some point you gotta put your big girl pants on.
And get on with it.
And figure out a way to make things better.
Life is not always fair. That is a reality.
There are so many things that happened in my life.
That I do not think were fair at all.
But I learned from it.
And I moved on with newfound knowledge that just made me better.
And so it's your job to take responsibility over your life.
And make a difference.
The people who led you astray are not gonna do that.
And it's not their responsibility.
Honestly, it's up to you.
What you do with your life.
That can be a little scary or intimidating.
But it also makes you feel empowered.
Like, it feels good to feel like I can choose for myself.
I can make a difference for myself.
And as you do that more and more, you become more confident.
And you really see the proof of that
And it feels amazing
Honestly by the way I have a whole video about victim mentality
So I'll link that here
I used to be one, so no judgment
But my life really did a whole one eighty when I changed this pattern
I could have never made a change
If I was constantly wallowing and feeling bad for myself
And blaming everyone else
And just recycling the same stories over and over again
And the same excuses like I would've done absolutely nothing.
I would have still been in the same spot.
So I highly recommend checking that out.
If you resonate with this and it's again.
No judgment or shame, I've been there. Trust me.
All right guys, that is it for all of my tips for the day.
I have so many more when it comes to this topic.
So just let me know if you want to see a part two.
And I'll film that for you.
If you enjoyed this video, I would love for you to subscribe.
And stick around for the next one
And again you can check out my social media
If you want to see more of my personal life and follow along
And we can keep these shots going
But thank you so much for watching
And I will see you in my next video